（中央公園咖啡廳）
Out of all of us, who do you think will get married next?
我們所有人裡 你想下一個結婚的會是誰？
Probably Monica and Chandler.
大概是摩妮卡和錢德
Could I have a pack of Newport Lights?
給我一包新港淡煙？
We don't sell cigarettes, but they do across the street.
我們沒有賣煙，對街有賣
That'd be great. Thanks.
那太好了，謝謝
Melissa Worbert. I don't think I have the energy for this.
馬利莎伍伯，我沒有力氣應付她
Oh, my God! Ray-Ray Greene?
我的天！瑞瑞葛林？
怎麼樣？！
You've been MlA for seven sorority newsletters.
你是我們社團連續7期週報主角
What's up with you?
你怎麼樣？
Why don't I tell you over here?
我們到那邊去再說？
So last I heard you were gonna get married.
上次我聽說你要結婚了
Poor Ray-Ray.
可憐的瑞瑞
Oh, no. It's all good.
不，其實很好
-I actually work at Ralph Lauren. -Shut up!
-我現在替洛夫羅蘭工作 -閉嘴！
I will not. I'm the divisional head of men's sportswear.
我不，我是男裝運動服飾的分區主管
Shut up more! Are you friends with Ralph?
再閉嘴！你是洛夫的朋友嗎？
-Oh, please. -Are you?
-拜託 -你是嗎？
No.
不是
We have to have dinner. What are you doing tomorrow?
我們一定要一起吃飯 你明天做什麼？
-Tomorrow. I don't know. -You're having dinner with me.
-明天，我不知道 -你要和我吃晚飯
Shut up.
閉嘴
I've gotta go. This has been so great.
我要走了，看到你真好
Oh, there you are.
哦，這兒
So listen, just call me. Here's my card.
打電話給我，這是我的名片
-You're in real estate? -No, that's an old card.
-你在做房地產？ -不，那是舊名片
I got out of that to do something where I could...
我必須離開那工作去做些…
help people and make a difference.
可以幫助別人和改變什麼的工作
What do you do now?
現在你做什麼？
I'm a party planner.
宴會規劃
-I'll see you tomorrow. -Okay.
-明天見 -好
Look who's back. It's Ray-Ray.
看誰回來了，是瑞瑞
That was my friend, Melissa, from college.
那是我大學的朋友馬利莎
She seems really, really fun!
她看起來很有意思！
She's actually sweet, and we used to be very close.
她真的很甜，我們曾經很親近
Wait a minute. She's not the one who you...?
等一下，她不是那個你…？
Who you what? Who you what?
你怎樣？你怎樣？
-Yes. -Wow!
-是 -哇！
Wow, what? Who you what?
哇，什麼？你怎樣？
Oh, it's not a big deal.
沒什麼大不了
They were lovers.
他們是情人
-What? -What?
-什麼？ -什麼？
No, we weren't. It was nothing.
不，我們不是情人，沒有什麼
It was one night, senior year, and we went to a party...
大四的一天晚上，我們去參加舞會…
had a lot of sangria, and you know, ended up...
喝了很多桑格利塔，你知道，結果…
kissing for a bit.
我們接吻了
So that's two of my wives.
我的兩個老婆都是同性戀
The One With Rachel's Big Kiss
本集播出：瑞秋的吻
rainystar壓制iPod-MP4
So this is where the band is. And here's the bar.
這是樂隊的所在，這兒是吧檯
And all these pins have people's names on them. Rach, here you are.
這些大頭針上有人名 瑞秋，你在這裡
Why don't we just put me with a Manhattan in my hand...
為什麼不給我一杯曼哈頓…
talking to the cute bartender.
讓我和可愛的酒保聊天
These pins aren't for playing, are they?
這些大頭針不是用來玩的，是不？
The red are my guests, and the blue are yours.
紅的是我的客人，藍色的是你的
This is so sad. I only have like 10 pins.
真可憐，我只有10個客人
Chandler, relax. It's not a contest.
錢德，輕鬆一點，這不是比賽
Certainly not a close one.
不是實力相近的比賽
Hey, Rach.
瑞秋
Stop picturing it!
不要再想了！
I think that's it. The seating chart is done. This is our wedding.
我想這樣可以了，座位表好了 這是我們的婚禮
They all look like they're having fun.
他們看來玩得很開心，不是嗎
So where are my parents gonna be?
我爸媽坐哪裡？
Well, if this is the wedding hall...
如果這是結婚禮堂…
your parents would be over here at home in Queens.
你父母會在皇后區的家裡
They're not invited? Oh, no, they're gonna be crushed!
他們沒有被邀請？ 不，他們一定會很傷心！
Why would they think they're invited?
為什麼他們以為會被邀請呢？
You got me. I don't...
你問倒我了，我不…
-Joey! -Look, I thought parents were coming.
-喬伊！ -我以為父母都會來
Your parents are coming. Chandler's are coming.
你的父母會來，錢德的父母也會來
Ross' parents are coming.
羅斯的父母也會來
Ross' parents are my parents.
羅斯的父母就是我的父母
Well, see, parents are coming.
看，父母們都會來
-We should invite them. -You just want more blue pins.
-我們應該請他們 -你只是想要更多的藍色大頭針
Well, this is just sad.
這實在太慘了
All right. Maybe I can fit them in if I just do some rearranging.
好，也許能把他們排進來 不過要重新安排位子
Rachel may have to sit at the bar.
瑞秋可能要坐在吧檯
That is not a problem.
沒有問題
-Maybe you'll order a little sangria. -Get out of here!
-也許你可以叫一杯桑格麗塔 -去你的！
These are our tuxedos. If you like anything, we can make a deal.
這是我們的禮服 如果有你喜歡的，可以便宜些
Anything at all. But these are the three that Monica pre-approved.
全部都可以 但這三件是摩妮卡先核准的
Thanks a lot for hooking me up.
謝謝你替我們拉到關係
And I want you to know that I want you to attend our wedding as my guest.
我想請你參加我們的婚禮做我的客人
I'm Monica's maid of honor.
我是摩妮卡的伴娘
Okay, don't try to blue-pin me.
別想把我變成藍色大頭針
-Well, these look nice. -They are nice.
-這些不錯 -是不錯
When celebrities are done with them, they send them back.
名人穿過這些之後，就送回來這兒
-You mean like for award shows? -Some of them.
-你是指像頒獎典禮之後？ -有些是
They've been down the red carpet with people yelling...
它們都上過紅地毯，被人叫著：
"Who are you wearing? You look fabulous!"
「你穿的是誰的？你看來棒極了！」
Might I suggest watching a little more ESPN...
容我建議您多看一點ESPN…
and a little less E!.
少看一點藝人八卦節目！
Okay. Who wore those?
誰穿過這些？
-Well, this one's Tom Brokaw. -Not bad.
-這是湯姆布魯克穿過的 -不錯嘛
This one is Paul O'Neill.
這是保羅歐尼爾穿過的
Who's that?
他是誰？
He plays for the Yankees. Seriously, ESPN.
他是洋基隊的球員 真的，多看ESPN
Just once in a while. Have it on in the background.
有的時候，開著它當背景也好
-This one was Pierce Brosnan. -Pierce Brosnan?
-這是皮爾斯布魯斯南穿過的 -皮爾斯布魯斯南？
Are you serious?
真的嗎？
007?
007？
This is James Bond's tux? I have to get married in James Bond's tux.
這是詹姆士龐德的燕尾服？我一定要 穿詹姆士龐德的燕尾服結婚
It's a pretty cool tux.
很酷
It's not just that. I would be England's most powerful weapon.
不只如此，我會是 英格蘭最強力的武器
A jet-setting heartbreaker on Her Majesty's secret service.
女王陛下的秘密特務 四處旅遊的斷腸人
A man who fears no one, with a license to kill.
有著殺人執照，什麼都不怕的男人
Would Monica let me wear this?
摩妮卡會不會讓我穿這件？
We should really learn how to play the real way.
我們應該學真正的玩法
I like our way.
我喜歡我們的玩法
Chess!
將軍！
-Nice move. -Yeah.
-走的好 -是啊
I hooked Ross and Chandler up with tuxedos. Do you need one?
我替羅斯和錢德找到 燕尾服，你需要嗎？
No, I'm not wearing a tux.
不，我不穿燕尾服
-What are you gonna wear? -Multi-colored robes.
-你要穿什麼？ -多彩的袍子
And maybe a hat.
也許戴一頂帽子
-Does Monica know about this? -No.
-摩妮卡知道嗎？ -不
Can I please be there when you tell her?
你告訴她時我可以在場嗎？
You want to go to a movie tonight?
晚上要不要去看電影？
I'm having dinner with Melissa.
我要和馬利莎吃飯
Can I come?
我可以來嗎？
I won't talk. You'll just hear my video camera.
我不說話，你只會聽見 我的攝影機的聲音
-What? What's going on? -Can I tell her?
-什麼？怎麼回事？ -我可以告訴她嗎？
Do you want what happened, or Joey's lewd version?
你要真正發生的事 還是喬伊的淫蕩版本？
Joey's.
-喬伊的 -好
I had this college friend...
我有一個大學朋友…
and I made the mistake of telling Joey that one time...
我不應該告訴喬伊有一次…
she and I, you know, kissed a little bit.
她和我接吻了
Yeah, I'm sure that happened.
是啊，我相信有的
-It did. -Sure.
-真的 -當然
Hey. It happened.
真的發生了
It was senior year. It was after the Sigma Chi luau...
是大四那年，那是一次社團聚會…
and Melissa and I got very drunk.
我和馬利莎喝得大醉
And we ended up kissing. For several minutes.
結果我們兩個接吻了 好幾分鐘呢
Which means she had a couple spritzers and a peck on the cheek.
意思是她喝了幾杯，輕輕吻在臉頰上
Why are you taking this away from me?
你為什麼要奪走這件事呢？
Why is it so hard for you to believe?
為什麼這麼難讓你相信？
Okay. I just didn't know that you were a lesbian.
好吧，我不知道你是同性戀
I'm not saying that I'm a lesbian. I'm just saying that this happened.
我不是說我是同性戀 我只是說那件事發生了
It just seems pretty wild. And you're so...
只是覺得很狂野，你是這麼地…
vanilla.
乖寶寶
Vanilla? I'm not vanilla. I do lots of crazy things.
乖寶寶？我不是乖寶寶 我做很多瘋狂的事
I mean, I got drunk and married in Vegas.
我喝醉了，在拉斯維加斯結婚
To Ross.
和羅斯
If you don't believe me...
如果你不相信我…
just come with me to dinner tonight and she'll tell you.
今晚和我一起去吃飯，她會告訴你
Okay. Because I can't picture it.
好吧，可是我想像不出來
You should get inside my head.
你該看看我腦袋裡的劃面
Guess what I got for your wedding?
猜我為你的婚禮弄到什麼？
A freakishly thin date with a hanger for a head?
頭像掛衣架，瘦巴巴的伴？
Rachel hooked me up with a tux. But not just any tux.
瑞秋替我弄到一件燕尾服 但不是隨便一件
Batman's tux!
是蝙蝠俠的！
-What? -That's right.
-什麼？ -沒錯
Made expressly for Val Kilmer, and worn by him in the hit film...
特別定做給方基墨的 讓他穿在票房冠軍電影…
that Batman film he was in.
那部他演的蝙蝠俠電影裡
You can't wear that. I'm wearing the famous tux.
你不能穿那件 我要穿名人的燕尾服
If you wear that, it'll make mine less special.
怎樣？如果你穿那件 會讓我的不那麼特別的
You need something to to make it special?
你需要用一些東西來讓那天特別嗎？
You have the most special thing of all.
喂！你有了最特別的一樣
You are marrying the woman you love.
你娶了你愛的女人
Don't take away my cool thing. Pretty please?
不要搶走我的鋒頭，拜託囉？
"Pretty please?" Not very 007.
「拜託囉？」不怎麼007
If you were getting married, I'd never do anything to upset you.
如果你要結婚 我不會做任何讓你生氣的事
-You slept with my sister. -That was pretty 007.
-你和我妹妹上床 -那很007
All right, I figured it out.
好，你來了 好，我想出辦法來了
I'm gonna take 2 tables of 8, add your parents...
我把8個人的這兩桌，加上你父母…
and make them into 3 tables of 6.
變成6個人的三桌
And I called the caterer. We are good to go!
我已經通知了辦席的人，都弄好了！
Yeah. They're not coming.
他們不來了
What?
什麼？
They think that you only invited them because of me.
他們覺得你是因為我才邀請他們的
They feel unwanted.
他們覺得不被歡迎
That's too bad. It's true. But too bad.
真糟糕，是真的，但真糟糕
If you could just call my mom.
你可以打電話給我媽
Just let her know you want them there.
讓她知道你希望他們去
This is a woman who has sent you many lasagnas.
她送過你很多很多千層面
No, she hasn't.
不，她沒有
Is it her fault if some didn't make it to you?
有些沒送到你手裡不是她的錯
What am I gonna say?
我要說什麼？
Tell them you mixed up invitations. No, blame it on the post office.
告訴她請帖搞亂了，不，怪郵局好了
They hate the post office. And the Irish.
他們最恨郵局，還有愛爾蘭人
But I don't think you could blame it on them.
不過我想你不能怪到他們頭上
Hello? Yeah, hi. Mrs. Tribbianni? This is Monica Geller.
喂？你好，崔比亞尼太太？ 我是摩妮卡蓋勒
I'm just calling to say that I really hope you can make the wedding.
我想告訴你我們很希望 你們能來參加婚禮
Apparently some of our invitations weren't delivered.
我們很多請帖都沒寄到
I guess there was some screw-up at the damn post office.
我猜又是可惡的郵局搞砸的
Tell me about it!
就是嘛！
Yeah, the U.S. Post Office? No. More like U.S. Lost Office.
什麼美國郵局嘛？更像是美國遺失局
What are they, Irish?
他們搞什麼嘛，都是愛爾蘭人嗎？
Anyway, his name's Allen. And we've been going out for three years.
他叫艾倫，我們在一起三年了
He was my first client when I became a party planner.
他是我做宴會規劃的第一位客戶
He was actually planning a party for his girlfriend at the time.
那時他正要規劃給他女朋友的宴會
Oh, well.
嗯
-He was Theta Beta Pi at Syracuse. -That's great.
-他是雪城大學貝塔拍社團的 -真好
-Were you ever in a sorority? -Of course.
-你參加過社團嗎？ -當然
Yes. I was a Thigh Mega Tampon.
我是大腿大衛生棉條的成員
What one?
哪一個？
We were huge too. But they had to shut us down...
我們也很龐大，但後來被關掉了…
when Regina Phalangie died of alcohol poisoning.
因為芮吉娜菲蘭基死於酒精中毒
Isn't it a shame when one girl ruins it for the whole bunch?
真是糟糕，一個女孩就毀了大家
Anyway...
不管了…
Speaking of drinking too much, I told Phoebe...
講到喝太多，我告訴菲比…
about that crazy night after the Sigma Chi luau where we made out.
在席格□社很瘋那晚，我們親吻的事
What?
什麼？
Remember we.. Come on, we had sarongs on and the coconut bikini tops.
記得我們…我們穿著沙龍 還有椰子殼比基尼上衣
We went back to the house and got really silly...
之後我們回到家，在那兒瘋癲…
and we made out.
然後我們接吻了
Wow, Ray-Ray, I have no idea what you're talking about.
瑞瑞，我不知道你在說什麼
Really?
真的？
Ross is Batman.
羅斯是蝙蝠俠
Well, he did manage to keep his identity secret for a long time.
他是把身份掩護了很久
Rachel got Ross the tuxedo that Val Kilmer wore in Batman.
瑞秋替羅斯弄到 方基墨在蝙蝠俠裡穿的燕尾服
Batman is so much cooler than James Bond.
蝙蝠俠比詹姆士龐德酷多了
-What? 007 has all those gadgets. -Batman has a utility belt.
-什麼？007有很多的工具 -蝙蝠俠有工具腰帶
-007 has a fancy car. -Batman has the Batmobile.
-007有很炫的車 -蝙蝠俠有蝙蝠車
-007 gets all the ladies. -Batman has Robin.
-007有很多女人 -蝙蝠俠有羅賓
We get ESPN, right?
我們有ESPN台，對吧？
How about you go put on your 007 tuxedo, and I'll make you a martini?
你何不穿上你的007燕尾服 我替你調一杯馬丁尼
I don't like martinis.
我不喜歡馬丁尼
-A Yoo-Hoo with a funny straw? -Yum.
-一杯搖搖飲料，用一隻搞笑吸管？ -好的
I know the invitation says 6 p.m.
請帖上寫晚上6點
But does that mean get there at 6, or the show starts at 6?
是指6點入席，還是6點開始表演？
The show?
「表演」？
Right, the wedding. Gotcha.
對，婚禮，知道了
But weddings start a little late, right?
不過婚禮會晚一點開始，對不？
Have you ever been to one of my weddings?
你有參加過我規劃的婚禮嗎？
Well, it's the same day as my niece's christening...
那天我侄女受洗…
and I want my parents to see me.
我希望我父母能看到我
My part's in the beginning. I'm not in the rest of the show.. Wedding.
我的部份是在開始時 不在其他部份的表演…婚禮
The wedding starts at 6.
婚禮6點開始
Okay. I totally hear you.
好，我聽到了
How about this? I vamp till they get there.
這樣如何？我可以表演到他們到達
You'll "vamp"?
你要「表演」？
Like warm up the crowd. Ask where they're from.
像是和觀眾打打屁，問他們從哪兒來
In Joey Tribbiani, you get a minister and an entertainer.
因為喬伊崔比亞尼在時 你有教士和演藝人員
I'm a "ministainer."
我是一位「教演人」
There's no one better. There's no one greater.
沒有更好的，沒有更偉大的
How can you not remember us kissing?
你怎能不記得我們接吻的事？
I don't know. I don't remember a lot of things that never happened.
我不知道，我不記得那些 從沒發生過的事
Remember, we were on the sleeping porch? We couldn't stop giggling.
記得我們在睡覺的廊子裡 一直笑一直笑？
Our coconuts kept knocking together.
我們的椰子殼撞在一起
Somewhere Joey's head is exploding.
喬伊的頭在某處爆炸了
I don't want to make you uncomfortable...
我不想讓你不舒服…
but I told Phoebe it happened, and she doesn't believe me.
但我告訴菲比發生的事，她不相信我
I'm sorry. I mean, if I thought it happened, I would say it.
對不起，如果我認為 它發生了，我會承認的
Maybe I passed out and you did stuff to me while I was sleeping.
也許我昏過去了 你在我睡覺時對我做了什麼
It's okay, you don't have to do this. I believe you.
沒關係，你不必這麼做，我相信你
If you say you kissed Melissa, then you kissed Melissa.
如果你說你吻了馬利莎 那麼你就吻了馬利莎
-Thank you, Phoebe. -Okay.
-謝謝，菲比 -好
-But she didn't. -I know.
-可是她沒有 -我知道
You carry that around?
你帶著它走來走去？
I find it to be something of a conversation piece.
是的，我發現它是個好話題
-Between you and...? -Gunther.
-和…？ -阿甘
Why don't we put them on?
我們何不穿上？
Get a picture of Batman and James Bond, together.
拍一張蝙蝠俠和 詹姆士龐德一起的照片
I would, but my pants are a little tight.
我很願意，但我的褲子小了一點
A little tight? I could see 00 and 7 in those things.
小了一點？我可以看到 裡面的兩個0和一個7
I was looking forward to wearing our celebrity tuxes together.
真糟糕 我很期待我們一起穿名人燕尾服呢
-So you're not gonna be wearing yours? - Are you kidding? It's Batman's tux!
-你不穿你的了？ -你開玩笑？是蝙蝠俠的燕尾服！
Let me try it on.
我試穿看看
Okay. But just the jacket. 00 and 7 are not getting in there.
好，只有外套 兩個0和一個7不要進去
Holy double-vented comfort, Batman!
雙面通風的舒適，蝙蝠俠！
What's this?
這是什麼？
An invitation to the At First Sight premiere?
《真情難捨》首映請帖？
Val Kilmer didn't wear this in Batman.
方基墨沒有在《蝙蝠俠》裡穿這件
He wore it to the premiere of a fruity love story where he was a blind guy.
他穿這件去參加 他演瞎子的那部文藝愛情片首映
Let me see that.
給我看
Oh, man.
老天
The only super power you have is the slightly heightened sense of smell.
你唯一的超能力是稍微強化的嗅覺
Can I talk to you guys for a second?
可以和你們談談嗎？
I give up. Whatever you want, you can have it.
我放棄了，你要怎樣就怎樣吧
You want to sing a song or do a dance?
你要唱歌還是跳舞？
You want your mom at the altar screaming racial slurs? I don't care.
還是要你媽在祭壇前 尖叫種族崎視的字眼？我都不在乎
I just want to thank you guys for what you did for my parents.
我只是要謝謝你們為我父母做的一切
They're so happy to be a part of your special day.
他們很高興能參加你們特別的一天
Tell them we're glad they're coming.
告訴他們我們很高興他們會來
I will. Oh, check out what they got me to wear for the ceremony!
我會的，看看他們替我準備 參加婚禮的衣服！
I wear it like this when I marry you guys. And then this...
我替你們證婚時這樣穿，然後…
is for party time.
在宴會時這樣穿
It happened. I am telling you it happened.
它發生了，我告訴你它發生了
It was great meeting you.
很高興認識你
And, Rachel? I don't think I'll be calling you because...
瑞秋？我想我不會 打電話給你，因為…
you know, you've gotten weird.
你變得好奇怪
Take care, you guys.
保重，兩位
Wait a minute. Okay, look.
等一下，好，聽著
That night was the one wild thing I've ever done in my life.
那天晚上是我所做過 最狂野的一件事
I won't let you take it away.
我不會讓你奪去它
So if you don't remember that, maybe you'll remember this...
如果你不記得那件事 也許你會記得這個…
Oh, my God. You love me.
我的天，你愛我
What?
什麼？
Of course I remember. I think about it all the time.
我當然記得，這些日子裡我一直想著它
I can still hear the coconuts knocking together...
我還能聽到椰子殼碰在一起的聲音…
I didn't want to tell you, because I didn't think you'd return my love...
我不想告訴你，因為我不覺得 你會回報我的愛…
Look who's being suddenly shy.
看是誰突然變得害羞
You have to feel what I feel.
你一定和我一樣感覺
Nobody can kiss that good and not mean it.
沒人能不是真心而吻得那麼好
I'm just a good kisser.
我的吻功很好
Shut up.
閉嘴
I'm sorry.
對不起
You don't have to be sorry.
你不必抱歉
I'm obviously kidding.
我在開玩笑
I'm not in love with you. I'm not in love with her.
我沒愛上你，我沒愛上她
I don't hear coconuts banging together.
我沒聽到椰子殼撞在一起
I don't picture your face when I make love to my boyfriend.
我和男友做愛時沒幻想你的臉
Anyway, I gotta go.
我要走了
A kiss goodbye?
親一下再見？
No? Okay.
不要？好吧
I mean, I had no idea that that would...
我不知道那會…
What the hell was that?
這是怎麼回事？
Just wanted to see what all the fuss was about.
想看看這一場混亂是怎麼來的
-And? -I've had better.
-然後？ -我有過更好的
I found one that fits.
我找到一件合身的
Well, you know what they say? 23rd time's a charm.
是啊，人們常說 第23次是最好的一次
Look at you, all handsome.
看看你，好英俊
-Whose is it? -Does it matter?
-是誰穿過的？ -有關係嗎？
All that matters is that you look so handsome.
唯一重要的是你看來很英俊
-Whose is it? -I don't want to say.
-是誰的？ -我不想講
Come on, I don't care. Whose is it?
我不在乎，是誰的？
Diane Keaton.
黛安基頓